Mss.Rec.2 Mss.Rec.2
American Philosophical Society
Tuscarora Material
1948-1949
Mss.Rec.2
American Philosophical Society
30.0 Tape(s)
Recorded by Anthony Wallace in 1948 and 1949 at the Tuscarora Reservation in Niagara County, New York. Contains folkloric stories, tribal histories (especially relating to the 18th and 19th centuries), autobiographical stories, reminiscences, word lists, and descriptions of tribal government, organizations, and customs. Almost all stories are given in both Tuscarora and English. Originally recorded on 16 wire spools, transfered to open reel tape in 1950.
30 open reel tapes (14 hr., 38 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
Gansworth, Nellie
Green, Jonas
Hewitt, David
Mt. Pleasant, William
Printup, Denny
Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
Rickard, Edgar
Rickard, Edward
Smith, Daniel
Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
Related Archival Materials
A transcript of the majority of the recordings can be found in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics collection (Mss.497.3.B63c). Related material, including photographs of the recordings sessions, can be found in the Anthony Wallace papers (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Anthony Wallace in 1950. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Note on Restrictions
Access to recordings of Thematic Apperception Tests or Rorschach tests is restricted.
Great Britain. Treaties, etc. United States, 1794 Nov. 19; Herbs; Indian Defense League of America; Indians of North America--Migrations; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826--Manuscripts; Migration, Internal--United States--History--19th century; Military service, Voluntary--United States; Philippines--Description and travel; Philippines--History--Philippine American War, 1899-1902; Porter, Peter B. (Peter Buell), 1773-1844; Six Nations. Great Law of Peace; Sound recordings; Spanish-American War, 1898; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--Medicine; Tuscarora Indians--North Carolina--History; Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; United States--History--French and Indian war, 1755-1763; United States--History--War of 1812
- Audio recordings
  - A story about a large snake, 1948-07-25; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:48; Smith, Daniel; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Scope and Contents note
    Re-told as "The Big Serpent" by Nellie Gansworth. See Related Recording.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Wire recording) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Snakes; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The little folk and the little boy who played with them in the woods, 1948-07-25; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:45; Smith, Daniel; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Story re-told by Nellie Gansworth as "The story of the boy who abused the false face". See: Related Recording
    Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - A story about herbs, 1948-07-25; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:33; Smith, Daniel; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    The speaker is a Tuscarora herbalist. Re-told by Nellie Gansworth as "A Medicine Vision." See: Related Recording.
    Herbs; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Medicine; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Visions
  - A story about what the old-timers used to call the strongest animal on earth, 1948-07-25; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:20; Smith, Daniel; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-told by Nellie Gansworth as "The strongest animal on earth." See: Related Resource.
    Animals--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - How the black lizard became small, 1948-07-25; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:18; Smith, Daniel; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-told by Nellie Gansworth. See Related Recording.
    Animals--Folklore; Lizards--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - How the informant started to get interested in herbs, 1948-07-25; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:33; Smith, Daniel; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    The speaker is a Tuscarora herbalist. Story re-told by Nellie Gansworth. See: Related Recording
    Herbs; Tuscarora Indians--Medicine; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - How the informant learned to use the English language, 1948-07-25; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:58; Smith, Daniel; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Includes some questions by interviewer.
    English language--Acquisition; Tuscarora Indians--Education; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - How the Tuscaroras came to leave North Carolina, 1948-07-25; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:35; Smith, Daniel; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-told by Nellie Gansworth. See: Related Resource.
    Migration, Internal--United States--History--18th century; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--North Carolina--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Ottawa speech, 1947; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    Consists of short clips of Ottawa speech by an unidentified female speaker. These clips are found in between other recordings on the original wire recording. Wire was first used by Jane Willets in recording Ottawa in Michigan in 1947. This wire was later re-used by Anthony Wallace for recordings of Tuscarora in New York state.
    Michigan; Ottawa language
  - The story of the boy who abused the false face, 1948-07-29; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:21; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-telling of "The little folk and the little boy who played with them in the woods" told by Dan Smith. (See Related Recording.) Continuation of story begun of beginning of wire 2. The first 2-feet of the wire on this spool was discarded by the collector due to tangling.
    Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The Big Serpent, 1948-07-29; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:08; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-telling of "A story about a large snake" told by Dan Smith. See: Related Recording.
  - A Medicine Vision, 1948-08-03; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:51; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-telling of "A story about herbs" from Dan Smith. See Related Recording.
  - The strongest animal on earth, 1948-08-03; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:10; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-telling of Dan Smith's "A story about what the old-timers used to call the strongest animal on earth." See: Related Recording.
  - How the black lizard became small, 1948-08-11; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:15; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-telling of Dan Smith's story of the same name. See Related Recording.
  - A Story about the Salt War, 1948-08-12; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    At time of recording, the speaker was Grand President of the Indian Defense League of America.
    Sanborn (N.Y.); Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language
  - A Story about General Peter A. Porter, 1948-08-12; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:20; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    The General identified on the recording as Peter A. Porter is actually Peter Buell Porter. At time of recording, the speaker was Grand President of the Indian Defense League of America.
    Porter, Peter B. (Peter Buell), 1773-1844; Sanborn (N.Y.); Tuscarora language; United States--History--War of 1812
  - How some Tuscaroras migrated to Kansas, 1948-08-12; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:41; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    "[Kansas migration in 1840s. Rickard's grandpa was there.] [Time of Mexican war.] [About 1840 my grandpa was young man, died 94.]" At time of recording, the speaker was Grand President of the Indian Defense League of America.
    Kansas; Mexican War, 1846-1848; Migration, Internal--United States--History--19th century; Sanborn (N.Y.); Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language
  - The Origin of Scalping, 1948-08-12; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Sanborn (N.Y.); Scalping; Tuscarora Indians--History
  - How the Tuscaroras moved south to the Carolinas and then back north to the Iroquois country, 1948-08-12; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:29; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Migration, Internal--United States--History--18th century; Sanborn (N.Y.); Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--North Carolina--History; Tuscarora Indians--Wars, 1711-1713; Tuscarora language
  - How the Tuscaroras helped the Americans in the War of 1812, 1948-08-12; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:12; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Sanborn (N.Y.); Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language; United States--History--War of 1812
  - The Indian Defense League of America, 1948-08-12; 03-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:23; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Includes discussion of the Jay Treaty, or Treaty of London. At time of recording, the speaker was Grand President of the Indian Defense League of America.
    Great Britain. Treaties, etc. United States, 1794 Nov. 19; Indian Defense League of America; Native American histories; Sanborn (N.Y.); Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--Medicine
  - An Anecdote about Captain Cusick's escape from a fight with Western Indians, 1948-08-12; 03-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:13; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Mexican War, 1846-1848; Sanborn (N.Y.); Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language
  - Tuscarora kinship terms, 1948-08-12; 03-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:26; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Sanborn (N.Y.); Tuscarora Indians--Kinship; Tuscarora language
  - The present Tuscarora terms for the Tuscarora words included in the Jefferson manuscript vocabulary in the American Philosophical Society Library, 1948-08-12; 03-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:39; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    At time of recording, the speaker, (Chief) William "Willy-hah" Mountpleasant carried the title of Head Sachem of the Tuscaroras, and had been Secretary to the Chief's Council for 16 years.
    Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826--Manuscripts; Tuscarora language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Seven English words whose Tuscarora counterparts may be the same as certain unidentified words in the Jefferson MS, 1948-08-12; 03-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Historical linguistics; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826--Manuscripts; Tuscarora language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Vocabulary of Tuscarora terms, 1948-08-13; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:26; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Vocabulary of Tuscarora numbers, 1948-08-13; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:16; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora language; Tuscarora language--Number; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora kinship terms [1 of 2], 1948-08-16; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:45:46; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Kinship; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora kinship terms [2 of 2], 1948-08-16; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:17; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Re-telling of Dan Smith's story about how he became interested in herbs, 1948-08-12; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:08; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - How the Tuscaroras came to leave North Carolina, 1948-08-12; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:57; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Re-telling of Dan Smith's story of same title. See: Related Recording.
    Migration, Internal--United States--History--18th century; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--North Carolina--History; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora terms for foods and beverages, 1948-08-12; 05-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:23; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Food; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Early Tuscarora superstitions concerning disease and magic, 1948-08-16; 05-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:29; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Lacrosse; Monsters--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Witchcraft--Folklore
  - Early Tuscarora superstitions concerning disease and magic (free translation), 1948-08-16; 05-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:35; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Lacrosse; Monsters--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Witchcraft--Folklore
  - The history of the Tuscarora people, 1948-08-16; 05-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:02; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Indians of North America--Migrations; Six Nations--History; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--Land tenure; Tuscarora Indians--North Carolina--History; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The history of the Tuscarora people (free translation), 1948-08-16; 05-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:17; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Tuscarora words for color, 1948-08-16; 05-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:06; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Colors, Words for; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora words for surface texture, 1948-08-16; 05-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Textures; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The History of the immigration of the Indians onto the North American Continent, 1948-08-30; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:07; Hewitt, David; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Indians of North America--Migrations; Native American histories; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The History of the immigration of the Indians onto the North American Continent, 1948-08-30; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:15; Hewitt, David; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Indians of North America--Migrations; Native American histories; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Guksui, or the Monster Bird, 1948-08-30; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:32; Hewitt, David; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Birds; Monsters--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Guksui, or the Monster Bird, 1948-08-30; 06-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:32; Hewitt, David; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Birds; Monsters--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The story of how a man escaped from a skeleton by hiding in a hollow log, 1948-08-30; 06-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:53; Hewitt, David; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Skeleton--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The story of how a man escaped from a skeleton by hiding in a hollow log, 1948-08-30; 06-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:35; Hewitt, David; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Skeleton--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The Story of the Golden Castle, 1948-08-30; 06-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:17; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - The Story of the Golden Castle, 1948-08-30; 06-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:12; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - The man who came with the message of peace, 1948-08-30; 06-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:30; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    This story is a version of the legend of Deganawida, or the Great Peacemaker, one of the traditional founders of the Haudenosaunee (or Iroquois) Confederacy.
    Deganawida; Iroquois Indians--History; Six Nations. Great Law of Peace; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The man who came with the message of peace, 1948-08-30; 06-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:03; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    This story is version of the legend of Deganawida, or the Great Peacemaker, one of the traditional founders of the Haudenosaunee (or Iroquois) Confederacy.
  - The story of a hunter who was cured by a man in a silvery canoe, 1948-08-30; 06-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:09; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    An Algonquian legend.
    Algonquian Indians--Folklore; Hunters--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The story of a hunter who was cured by a man in a silvery canoe, 1948-08-30; 06-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:45; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Algonquian Indians--Folklore; Hunters--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - A ghost story about the hunting party overtaken by nightfall, 1948-08-30; 06-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:19; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Hunters--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - History of the Temperance Society, 1948-09-02; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:42; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Temperance--Societies, etc.; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - History of the Temperance Society, 1948-09-02; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:39; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Temperance--Societies, etc.; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Easter Monday Morning Celebrations, 1948-09-02; 07-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:18; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Religion; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Easter Monday Morning Celebrations, 1948-09-02; 07-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:00; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Easter; Tuscarora Indians--Religion; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The life and religious activities of Samuel Jacobs, 1948-09-02; 07-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:36; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Indians--Religion; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The life and religious activities of Samuel Jacobs, 1948-09-02; 07-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Indians--Religion; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Story about the informant's Onondaga Great-Grandmother, 1948-09-02; 07-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:38; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Indians of North America--Migrations; Onondaga Indians; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--War of 1812
  - Story about the informant's Onondaga Great-Grandmother, 1948-09-02; 07-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:45; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Indians of North America--Migrations; Onondaga Indians; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--War of 1812
  - Story about a witch woman, 1948-09-02; 07-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:40; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Witches--Folklore
  - Story about a witch woman, 1948-09-02; 07-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:54; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Witches--Folklore
  - Brief autobiography of Jonas Green, 1948-09-02; 07-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:21; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Brief autobiography of Jonas Green, 1948-09-02; 07-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:41; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The witch woman who came from Canada, 1948-09-02; 07-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:01; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - The witch woman who came from Canada, 1948-09-02; 07-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - The education of the Jonas Green, 1948-09-02; 07-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:37; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Indians--Education; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The education of the Jonas Green, 1948-09-02; 07-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:20; Green, Jonas; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Indians--Education; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The Jefferson Vocabulary, 1948-08-30; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:53; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - The Skeleton Story, 1948-08-31; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:50; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - The Skeleton Story, 1948-08-31; 08-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Onondaga Turtle Song, 1948-08-31; 08-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:15; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    An improvised song, originally Seneca. Sung in Onondaga, with explanations in Tuscarora.
    Onondaga Indians--Music; Onondaga language; Seneca Indians--Music; Turtles; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Seneca Rabbit Song, 1948-08-31; 08-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:30; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Sung in Seneca, with explanations in Tuscarora.
    Rabbits--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca language; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Onondaga White Corn Story Song, 1948-08-31; 08-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:01; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Sung in Onondaga, with explanations in Tuscarora.
    Corn; Onondaga Indians--Music; Onondaga language; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - A Tuscarora Giant Story, 1948-08-31; 08-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:25; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Giants--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - A Tuscarora Giant Story, 1948-08-31; 08-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:18; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Giants--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The Story of the Devil's Hole, 1948-08-31; 08-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:15; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Includes medicine song sung in Seneca. Devils Hole is a natural ravine or hole near the Niagara River."
    Landforms--New York (State); Seneca Indians--History; Seneca Indians--Music; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The Story of the Devil's Hole, 1948-08-31; 08-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:31; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Includes medicine song sung in Seneca. Devils Hole is a natural ravine or hole near the Niagara River.
    Landforms--New York (State); Seneca Indians--History; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Wars; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)